Awesome, you've done fantastically to get this far.
太棒了，能走这么远你已经做得很好了
And for this section before we get started actually moving over to Hardhead. And moving over to JavaScript and understanding why we need to do that.
在我们实际转移到 Hardhat 和 JavaScript 并理解为什么要做这些的之前这一节
Let's understand a little bit about getting help and running into problems.
让我们先来了解一下如何寻求帮助并解决问题
So let's say we have our Funmi contract here that we just worked on.
就拿我们刚刚创建的这个 FundMe 合约来说
And we run into an error.
如果我们遇到了一个错误
Let's say for example, we forgot the payable keyword,
比方说，我们忘记 payable 关键字了
right, and we go ahead and compile this
好的，让我们继续并且编译它
compile fund, we did so.
编译 FundMe.sol
And we scroll down. And we see obviously, we have two errors here,
接着我们向下滚动，可以看到，这里我们有了两个错误
right, we're getting some errors, and we scroll down.
是的，我们收到了一些报错，接着向下滚动
And we see type error message dot value and call value can only be used and payable public functions,
我们可以看到类型错误(TypeError)，msg.value 和 callvalue() 只能在 payable public 函数中使用
make the function payable or using an internal function to avoid this error.
使这个函数成为 payable 的，或者使用 internal 函数来避免此错误
And then it goes ahead and gives the line that's airing.
然后它继续并给出了错误出现在哪一行
Now this error is pretty clear, this error code is pretty clear.
现在这个报错就很清楚了，错误代码非常清晰
It's saying Hey, make the function payable,
它在说，嘿，让这个函数变成 payable 的
or using an internal function to avoid this error, right?
或者使用 internal 函数来避免此错误，对吧？
This should be pretty easy to to add payable, and then recompile and be good to go.
很简单地在这里加上 payable，然后重新编译就可以了
And this is actually a good example of what to do when you run into errors.
这是一个很好的例子，它说明了当你遇到错误时该怎么做
When you run into errors. The first thing you want to do is
当你遇到错误时，第一件要做的事就是
you want to try to figure out exactly what's going on yourself based off of what the error says.
你要根据错误信息找出到底发生了什么
This one's pretty straightforward,
这个例子比较简单，
but some of them can be a little bit more obscure
但有一些也可能会比较晦涩
step one when trying to get unblocked trying to tinker and figure out errors yourself, right?
突破难题的第一步就是尝试自己纠正并解决错误，对吧？
Because maybe you go okay, I'll make this payable, right?
你可能会说，好吧，我在这里加上 payable 对吧？
And you go to save.
接着把它保存
And then it gives a different error saying, hey, you know, payable doesn't go here.
然后它就会报一个不同的错说，嘿，你得知道，payable 不是放在这里的
You resave you recompile it goes, Hey, we're still missing that payable thing.
重新保存重新编译，它会说，嘿，我们还是没有找到 payable
First step is always going to be trying to tinker and figure it out yourself.
第一步总是得依靠自己尝试纠正并解决问题
For this course,
在这门课上
I want you to limit tinkering, slash triaging to 20 minutes,
我希望你把纠错时间控制在 20 分钟以内
if you take more than 20 minutes to tinker and triage, then move on to the next step.
如果你花了 20 分钟时间还没有完成纠错，那么就要进入到下一步了
But I also want you to take at least 15 minutes yourself
但我仍然希望你至少要花 15 分钟时间来尝试独立解决
or be 100% Sure, you exhausted all options, you're completely out of ideas.
或者你已经 100% 确定，你已经尝试了所有的选择，没有任何新的想法了
So typically try to tinker try some stuff for 15 minutes.
所以一般来说，试着用 15 分钟的时间来进行纠错
And if you're under 15 minutes, and you're saying,
或者如果还不到 15 分钟，你就感觉
Hey, I'm 100% Certain I've tried everything that I can think of,
嘿，我已经百分之百确定我已经尝试了所有我能想到的方法了
then you can move on to the next step.
那么你就可以转移到下一步了
So step one, when you run into errors is always
所以第一步，当你遇到错误时你得先
going to be tinker and try to pinpoint exactly what's going on.
独自尝试修改错误并找出到底发生了什么事
Try to pinpoint exactly what's going wrong.
试着准确地指出到底哪里发生了问题
Step two, let's say you tinkered and you tried payable all over the place,
第二步，假设你已经尽可能地纠错并在各种地方都尝试添加了 payable
and you couldn't figure out what this error was and how to debug this here.
但你仍然不知道到底哪里出了错并且不知道该怎么调试这个 bug
Step two is always going to be Google the exact error and see if you can learn from that.
第二步就是要用 Google 进行精准纠错，并且看看你是否可以从中学到些什么
So zoom out a little bit, I'll roll my mouse over this, grab this,
缩小一点，把鼠标移到这里，选中这些
copy it, or quotes around it, and do exactly that,
复制它们，或者加上引号，然后检索
in Google search that exact error
在 Google 中精准寻找该错误
and take some time going through Google going through Stack Overflow going through Stack Exchange eath,
花一些时间去 Google 去 Stack Overflow 去 Stack Exchange Eth
and look to see if somebody has asked this question already.
看看有没有人已经问过这个问题了
And it looks like down here
看起来是在这里
looks like somebody has
看来其他人也遇到了
type error missed a value and call though can only be used on PayPal public functions.
类型错误："msg.value" 和 "callvalue()" 只能在 payable public 函数中使用
And if we scroll down, we see that somebody ran into exactly this.
如果我们往下滚动，可以看到有些人正好也遇到了这个问题
And they went ahead and solved it.
并且他们把这个问题给解决了
They go, I realized my mistake, I needed to add the PayPal keyword to my own implementation.
他们说，我意识到了自己的错误，我需要在我的实现中添加 payable 关键字
And they go ahead in this question, they've added the payable.
接着他们继续，在这个问题下他们添加了 payable
And hopefully this would give you the insight to say,
希望这能让你明白
Ah, okay, great. I do need to come back here and add payable.
啊，很好，我需要回到这里并且添加上 payable
Let's say this StackOverflow question didn't show up. Right?
假如 Stack Overflow 上并没有这个问题
This forum wasn't here. What do we do next?
没有这样一个讨论区，下一步该怎么办
So step one, tinker. Step two, Google the exact error,
第一步，改错，第二步，使用 Google 精准纠错
I'm going to do a step 2.5 That only is for this class,
现在我要做的第 2.5 步只适用于这门课
go to our GitHub, repo discussions, and or updates for this course,
去到我们的 Github 仓库的讨论区，或者这门课的更新
specifically, go to this GitHub repo, full blockchain solidity course, Jas,
特别是，去这个 Github 仓库，full-blockchain-solidity-course-js
it'll look a little bit different when you all get to it.
当你打开这里的时候界面可能会有一些不同
But come to this repo, and look in this chronological update section
不过最好是来看看这个仓库，按照时间顺序查看更新的内容
to see if there's an update on that section that you're doing.
看看有没有更新你正在做的部分
Obviously, since I'm recording right now, there's no update.
很明显，因为我现在还在录制所以这里没有什么更新
And if you don't get anything, feel free to jump into the discussion section.
如果你什么都没找到的话，请随时到讨论区看看
And ask a question in here, right,
并在这里提出问题
there's going to be a community of people looking to help each other out and looking to make this a lot of fun.
社区里会有人帮你一起看看，并让事情有趣起来
And the reason I say 2.5 is because
我之所以说这是第 2.5 步是因为
in the real world, you're not going to have our GitHub repo,
在实际工作中，你就没有我们的 Github 仓库了
when working on stuff outside of this course,
当你在做本课程之外的工作时
you're not going to have this GitHub repo.
你就没有这样的 Github 仓库可供参考了
So instead, in the real world, I'm still going to give you the keys,
所以作为替代，在实际工作中，我还是会给你一些其他诀窍
I'm going to give you what it takes to still unblock yourself on anything.
我仍然会告诉你消除自身障碍的一切方法
Okay. So number three is going to be asked a question on a forum,
好了，所以第三点就是在论坛上进行提问
like stack, exchange eath and Stack Overflow.
比如 Stack Exchange ETH 和 Stack Overflow
Stack Overflow is a question and answering tech forum like this, right?
Stack Overflow 是一个提供提问和解答的技术论坛，比如这个
You can ask tech questions, and then you can answer them as well.
你可以提出技术问题，也可以在上面进行回答
And as you can see, when you search for these issues, they'll show up
正如你所看到的，当你搜索这些问题时，它们就会出现
so Stack Overflow is more for general Role programming questions
所以 Stack Overflow 更适用于一般的编程问题
and Stack Exchange Aetherium or Stack Exchange eath Aetherium Stack Exchange,
而 Stack Exchange Ethereum 或者说 Stack Exchange Eth，Ethereum Stack Exchange
this is for more Aetherium or EVM based question
它更多的是以太坊或者 EVM 的问题为主
and all the solidity code that we're gonna be working with,
所有我们要处理的 Solidity 代码
whether it's polygon, whether it's avalanche, whether it's whatever,
无论是在 Polygon 还是 Avalanche 或者别的什么上
those questions are going to be valid here, and you can ask here.
这些问题都是可行的，能够在这里进行提问的
So what you'd want to do is you'd want to sign up or log in,
所以你要做的就是注册或者登录
and ask and format your questions on these forms,
然后在论坛上格式化地提出你的问题
you'll want to sign up for GitHub,
你得注册一下 Github
you want to sign up for Stack Exchange,
还要注册一下 Stack Exchange
you'll want to sign up for Stack Overflow,
还要注册 Stack Overflow
so you can participate in these forums.
这样你才能加入到这些论坛里来
In fact, if you haven't already, let's sign up for GitHub right now.
如果你现在还没有注册过 Github 的话，那我们现在就注册一下吧
And let me walk you through formatting one of these questions,
并且我会告诉你如何格式化地提出问题
because the better you format your questions, the better chance you have of actually getting the answer.
因为你提问的格式越好，就越有可能被回答
And remember, when asking questions on these forums,
而且要记住，当你在这些论坛提问时
when asking questions, in these discussion communities,
当你在这些讨论社区提问的时候
people answer these questions out of the goodness of their heart, right?
人们之所以回答这些问题是出于他们善良的热心
So if you don't get a response, there's a chance that maybe nobody knows,
所以你要是没有得到回应，有可能是没人知道答案
maybe it's your question isn't formatted very well, and etc.
也可能是你的提问格式不太好，等等
So we're going to learn how to ask really good questions here.
所以我们这里要学习一下如何问一个好问题
And if you're new to blockchain, do not skip this section. Okay,
如果你是个区块链新手的话，请不要跳过这一部分，好吗
this is going to be that piece that's going to give you the superpower
它能让你获得一种超能力
to unblock yourself from any coding issue you run into.
让你能够从遇到的任何代码问题中解脱出来
So don't skip this powerup. Be sure to follow along.
所以不要跳过这一部分，一定要跟着做
Okay. So if you don't have a GitHub already,
好了，如果你还没有 Github 账号
you do need an email to get started.
你需要一个电子邮箱才能开始
So I'm going to go ahead and sign in, I made a burner account just for this video.
现在我要登录邮箱了，我为这个视频创建了一个一次性账号
So what we're gonna do, we're gonna go ahead and sign up
所以我们现在要做的就是，注册账号
GitHub, enter your email
进入 Github，输入你的邮箱
and we hit Create Account, they're going to send us an email.
然后点击创建账号，他们会给我们发送一封邮件
So we're going to come back to our email,
所以我们回到我们的邮箱
and we got our launch code here, paste it in.
这里是我们的验证码，复制过来
And so a little bit of information.
接着提供一些信息
We're going to choose the free version.
我们要选择这个免费版本
and fantastic. We've now created a GitHub profile.
非常棒，我们现在已经创建好了一个 Github 账号
Now back over in the smart contract kid full blockchain solidity course, Jas,
现在回到 smartcontractkit/full-blockchain-solidity-course-js
I'm going to create a new discussion, a new thread,
我现在要创建一个新讨论(New discussion)，一个新的贴子
and I want you all to comment on to make sure you understand how to format and how to ask questions. Okay,
我希望你们都可以发表一下评论，以确保你们确实理解了该如何格式化地提问，OKay？
general thread for practicing. Question formatting. Oops.
练习提问格式的通用贴子！喔！！
And so let's go back here.
然后让我们回到这里
So first, I'm going to format this question poorly, two ways,
首先我会把问题的格式写的很糟糕，有两种方式
and then we're gonna format it really, really well.
接着我会把格式改的非常非常好
So the first way we're going to format it poorly, is by not giving enough information.
第一种糟糕的格式是，没有提供足够的信息
So what we're going to do is I'm gonna just copy this issue
我们要做的是，复制这一段
we're going to do is we'll just say like, Hey, I'm having trouble with remix and an error. Can someone help me?
接着要做的就是说，嘿，我在使用 remix 的时候报了一个错，谁能来帮帮我？
Why is this not a well formatted question?
为什么这不是一个格式良好的问题
If this is my question, there's not nearly enough information here,
如果这就是我的问题，那么这里并没有包含足够的信息
I, as a helper, have no idea what this person's asking.
如果我是来帮忙的，那我根本就无法知道这个人到底在问什么
So let's do something else. What I'm going to do is
我们再来做点别的，这回我们要做的是
I'm going to copy this entire contract all the fun, read outsole, paste it in here,
我要把整个 FundMe.sol 里的合约，都复制到这里
and go, Hi, I'm having issues here. Can someone help?
接着说，嗨，我遇到了一些问题，谁能来帮帮我
I'm gonna head start discussion
然后点击这里的 Start discussion
here want to hit start discussion, it formats this all weird.
当我点击了 Start discussion 之后，这里的格式变得非常奇怪
And once again, there's not really enough information here. I don't know what the issue is.
并且，这里还是没有足够的信息，我还是不知道问题出在了哪里
But at least with this one, we have some code, we have some way to actually debug.
但是至少相比第一个来说，这里有代码了，我们能够进行一些 debug 操作
So this is a little bit better. But it's still not that good.
这样的话略微好一点，但仍然不是太好
Let's go ahead and edit this. To make this even better.
我们来继续编辑它，让他变得更好一点
We hit three dots, we can hit edit,
点击这里的三个点，然后点击 Edit
what we can do is we can use something called Markdown syntax,
我们要做的是使用一种名为 Markdown 的语法
and highly recommend learning a little bit of markdown,
我强烈建议大家学习一些 Markdown 的用法
it's basically some syntax help make discussions on GitHub.
基本上就是一些帮助在 Github 上进行讨论的语法
And also, questions on Stack Overflow and Stack Exchange a lot easier.
并且同样使得在 Stack Overflow 和 Stack Exchange 上的提问容易了许多
So we're going to format this code
我们现在要把代码格式化
by adding these three backticks at the start,
方法是在代码开头添加三个点(译者注：即键盘左上角在 Esc 下面 Tab 上面，同时是波浪线的按键)
and then also at the end of our code.
然后在代码结尾处也是一样
And then additionally, next, the first three backticks, we're going to type so lid did T
另外，接下来我们还要在开头的三个点后面输入 so-li-di-ty
which tells the format or to to use solidity to format this code here.
以此表明此处格式化的是 solidity 代码
Now if we update discussion, we notice we get some nice highlighting here.
现在如果我们更新这个 discussion，我们注意到这里有一些高亮内容
So this becomes much, much easier to read.
这样就变得更加容易阅读了
Right? This is way easier to read now than than it was before.
好了，现在读起来比以前容易多了
However, it's still not specific enough.
但是，它还是不够具体
We've given a ton of code here, and we haven't given the specific answer.
我们给出了大量的代码，但没有给出具体的问题
So this is gonna be really hard for somebody to answer.
所以对很多人来说这个提问都很难回答
So let's make this more specific. So let's edit this question again. And let's specify,
那么我们来把它变得更具体一些，让我们再编辑一次这个问题，把它变得更具体一些
so we see here, our issue is specifically on this function.
可以看到，我们的问题出在这个函数上
We're going to copy this function and we're going to delete everything else in here.
我们要把这个函数复制过来，先把这里所有的东西都删掉
And now we have just this code inside of here.
现在我们只放了这么一小段代码在这里
Now we're going to make this really specific.
现在我要让它变得更具体一些
We're going to say, on this function, I'm running into an error.
我们会说，在这个函数中，我遇到了一个错误
And then what we're going to do is we're going to come back here, we're going to roll the over this.
然后我们要做的就是回到这边来，选中这一部分
We're going to copy this
我们要复制这一段
we could have pull our code if we want but we're going to format this error like this.
如果我们想的话，也可以把代码提取过来，但是我们这里就把报错信息格式化就行了
And then we're gonna say Can someone tell me What's going on? Update?
然后说，谁能来告诉我一下这是怎么回事？更新
Now this is a much, much easier question to debug. Right?
现在这就是一个非常非常容易 debug 的问题了，对吧
We have some minimalistic code, we have the error that we're getting.
我们的代码非常简洁，并且把报错信息也放上了
And we have Can someone tell me what's going on?
并且还问了“谁能告诉我这是怎么回事？”
Obviously, the answer to this would be to add payable to this.
显然，这个问题的答案就是把 payable 给加到这里
And that's what somebody would say, hey, like, you need to add payable to this,
有人来回答的话就会说，嘿，你好像要在这里加上 payable
I want you all to practice doing some formatting,
我希望你们都能练习一下这个格式
go ahead and add a comment on this with your own formatted question.
并且按照格式在这里回复一个你自己的问题
So that you understand how to actually do the formatting.
这样你就能理解如何使用这个格式了
And this markdown format. It's this format here,
并且，这个 markdown 格式，就是这里的这个格式
that's gonna be the exact same for asking questions on Stack Overflow, or Stack Exchange
同样也适用于在 Stack Overflow 或 Stack Exchange 上提问
for this course, go ahead and practice if you want to create more new discussions,
对本课程来说，如果你想创建更多的新讨论区，请继续练习
feel free to create new discussions.
你可以随意创建创建新的讨论区
If you want to use Stack Overflow or Stack Exchange eath
如果你想要使用 Stack Overflow 或 Stack Exchange Eth 的话
actually highly recommend you Stack Overflow or Stack Exchange eath as well,
其实我也更推荐你使用 Stack Overflow 或 Stack Exchange Eth
because those are gonna get indexed a lot better than GitHub here.
因为那里的索引要比 Github 这里好多了
However, feel free to ask questions, obviously, in this GitHub as well.
不过，显然在 Github 上你也是可以自由提问的
Now that I've given you kind of the basics rundown,
现在我已经告诉了你们一些基本要点
we're going to watch a video that I made that
接下来我们要来看一段我制作的视频
goes even deeper into why and how to format all these questions and what to use.
它将更深入地讲解为什么还有如何设置问题的格式，以及要使用什么工具
So let's go ahead and watch that.
让我们继续吧，来看看它
Every developer has run into this.
每一名开发者都在追求一个目标
Something breaks or maybe you don't know something,
出了些问题也可能你根本不知道出了什么问题
but you don't have time to let these stop you.
但你没有时间让这些妨碍你
There are a series of steps that one should take to maximize one's chances of solving any coding problem,
这里有一系列步骤可以让一个人最大限度地提升解决代码问题的能力
but you'd be surprised at how few developers currently use the superpower effectively,
但你会惊讶地发现，目前只有很少的开发者能够有效地使用这份超能力
our first one we'll spend the least time on,
我们的第一步花的时间最少
because it's just tinker and experiment.
因为就只是纠错和实验
When you run into an issue. Keep trying different things you think might work,
当你遇到问题的时候，尝试你认为可能有效的所有不同的方法
maybe try doing print statements throughout the file, learn some debugging tips,
可以试试对整个文件执行打印(print)语句，或是学习一些其他 debug 技巧
but don't be so cocky that you only do this first step.
但是不要骄傲地认为你只用做这第一步就够了
And this shouldn't just be random running around.
而且不要随意地胡乱尝试
This should be trying to pinpoint exactly what's going wrong in your code,
你应该尽可能精准地找到代码出错的地方
so that you can either ask an effective question,
这样你就可以提出一个高效的问题了
or figure it out yourself.
或者干脆自己就给解决了
So pinpoint exactly what's going wrong,
所以请精准地找到问题出在了哪里
because you'll need it for the next steps. Anyways,
因为接下来的步骤你无论如何都需要它
next, check the documentation.
下一步，检查文档
Not all tools have good documentation.
并不是所有工具都有十分完善的文档
But taking some time to explore documentation can be a quick way to find your answer,
但花点时间来研究文档是找到答案的一个快速方法
you'll want to learn how to search a webpage with Command F or Control F.
你要学习一下如何使用 "Command F" 或 "Ctrl F"
That way, you can look for specific keywords on a page,
这样，你就可以在页面上寻找特定的关键字
or hopefully they have a good search bar that works well.
或者祈祷他们有一个好用的搜索栏
Sometimes documentation can be really dense.
有的时候文档可能真的很繁复
So maybe you'll move to the next step, which is doing a web search.
所以你就需要进入到下一阶段，也就是到网络上搜索
At the end of the day, good software engineers are secretly just professional Googlers.
说到底，优秀的软件工程师私下里只是个专业的谷歌人
And this is one of their most powerful tools,
这是他们最强大的工具之一
being able to search the web for somebody else who has already run into the problem that you've just run into, and then solved it.
你能够在网上搜索到你遇到的问题，这些问题其他人很可能已经遇到过并解决了
Most search engines like Google have tools
大多数搜索引擎比如 Google 都有一些实用工具
you can use to get even more specific about what you're looking for.
你可以用它们来更具体地检索你要找的东西
Often for specific errors, the best thing to do
通常来说针对具体的问题，最好的方法就是
is actually just copy the exact error and paste it in the search bar with quotes
把错误信息复制粘贴到搜索栏并加上引号
or use the Asterix in spots, your error might be too specific.
或者在你可能出错的地方使用星号，如果不想过于具体的话
Most of the results you'll get will be from forums and q&a sites,
你得到的大多数检索结果都来自于论坛和问答网站
which leads us to our next step,
这就引出了我们的下一步
asking questions in these forums and q&a sites.
在这些论坛和问答网站上提问
Just make sure that before you ask a question,
只是在你提问之前得确认
you've done some ample Googling around yourself beforehand.
你已经在 Google 上做了充分的检索
This way you don't waste yours and anybody else's time.
这样你才不会浪费自己和其他人的时间
And by asking questions that you swear you will promise me
而且问过问题之后，希望你能发誓，向我承诺，
that at some point, you will go back and help other people learn as well got it good.
总有一天，你也会回去帮助其他人的学习，明白了？非常好
Before even asking your question though, we should learn where is going to be the best place to ask.
在你提问之前，我们首先应该知道哪里才是最好的提问地点
This is why I've categorized for different types of forums and QA sites,
这就是为什么我分类了四种不同类型的论坛和问答网站
feel free to pause to read them over.
你可以暂停下来阅读一遍
And here's some specific examples of each one of these
下面是每一种类型的一些具体例子
index code base forms like Stack Overflow,
以索引代码为基础的论坛比如 Stack Overflow
index repositories like GitHub issues,
索引仓库的比如 Github
index technology, specific forums, like our slash eat dev
索引特定技术的论坛，比如我们的 /ethdev (译者注：指 Reddit 的以太坊开发者版块，类似于国内常用的贴吧)
or unindexed discussion platforms like chainlink discord,
或者不索引什么的讨论平台，比如 Chainlink 的 Discord (译者注：Discord 是一种聊天社区，有些类似于国内常用的 QQ 或微信群)
one of the key differentiators in these categories is the index keyword.
这些分类的其中一个最重要的区别在于索引内容的不同
We typically want to ask questions on forums
我们通常希望在论坛上提出的问题
that web crawlers have gone through and stuck them in their database or index them
可以被网络爬虫获取，并把它们放入数据库中或者说索引它们
this way. And three weeks when we look back at the code that we wrote,
这样的话，当我们三周后再回顾我们所写的代码时
we can just Google what was going on when we forget what it does.
我们就可以在我们忘记它们的用法时 Google 一下了
And this will help out other developers who run into the same problem,
这也会帮助到其他遇到相同问题的开发人员
which in turn, they might go ahead and help you out later.
他们之后也可能会反过来继续帮到你
Ideally, most of your questions should be asked on one of these index forms for this reason
理想情况下，你的大多数问题都应该在这些论坛上提出
for their searchability and discoverability.
出于它们的可搜索性和可发现性
However, at some questions are a better fit for DMS, Twitter or discord that aren't index
然而，某些问题确实更适合于 DMS, Twitter 或 Discord 这种不设索引的地方
and we made a little chart here to figure out where's the best place to post your questions,
我们做了一个小图表来说明哪里是提问的最佳地点
feel free to pause the video take a look
你可以暂停下来看一看
or read our blog and the descriptions with the picture as well to take another look at it.
或者在阅读我们的博客和图片描述之后再来回看
And of course, before actually posting that in one of these forums,
当然了，在这些论坛提问之前
be sure to read their rules
一定要阅读一下它们的论坛规则，
as they might state that some kind of questions are specifically for Ben.
因为它们可能会说有些问题是专门禁止的
But basically the breakdown looks like this.
基本上来说分类是这样的
Theoretical big picture or opinionated questions can go great on general q&a forums like Quora
理论的，宏观的或者观点性的问题可以去一些通用的问答论坛，比如 Quora (译者注：类似于国内常用的知乎)
or specific technical forums like specific subreddits or discord forums,
或者是特定的技术论坛比如特定的 Reddit 版块或 Discord 论坛
specific coding questions can go on these forums as well,
特定的代码问题也可以发到这些论坛上
but will often get more eyes on coding forums
但我们通常会更倾向于发到代码论坛上
like Stack Overflow or Stack Exchange communities
比如 Stack Overflow 或 Stack Exchange 社区
often the question of Oh, should I post this on stack URL? flow or maybe a Stack Exchange community
经常会有这样的问题，哦！我应该把这个发到 Stack Overflow 还是 Stack Exchange 上
is incredibly blurry.
这个问题很模糊
And sometimes it doesn't really matter which one you post on.
很多时候你到底在这两个论坛中的哪一个上发帖并不重要
Now, if you run into a bug or an issue with a technology you're really familiar with,
现在，如果你遇到的 bug 或问题出自于一种你非常熟悉的技术
and you think it shouldn't be breaking,
并且你认为这不是你的原因
this is your chance to pop an issue into their open source code repository
那么这就是一个你向他们的开源代码库提出问题的机会
and potentially improve the tool.
并有可能因此而改进该工具
They don't have an open source code repository,
你说他们没有开源代码库？
you throw that closed source piece of shit into the garbage,
那你应该把这坨封闭代码的垃圾扔进垃圾堆
but just kidding closed source Tech has its place in our lives, too.
不过这只是句玩笑话，封闭式技术在我们的生活中也是有一席之地的
Additionally, if you're following a tutorial, and they have a Git repo associated with it,
另外，如果你正在跟随某个教程，并且他们有关联的 Git 仓库
like all of my videos that do,
就像我所有的视频那样
that's gonna be the best place to leave your issues.
那么那里就是解决你问题最好的地方
So as much as I hate to say it, putting your issues onto my GitHub repositories
虽然我不想这么说，但把你的问题放在我的 Github 仓库上
is going to be much more effective for us answering your questions than posting it in the YouTube comments.
对我们回答你的问题来说，要比放到 Youtube 评论区中高效得多
Now finally, Discord, element, email, text message or any other these unindexed chats
最后，Discord，Element，Email，短信或是任何无索引的聊天工具
are still good places to ask questions,
也是发问的好地方
but please try to use them as a last resort.
但请把它们作为你最后的手段
And if they do end up answering one of your questions,
如果他们真的回答了你的问题
maybe go back and add that question and answer to one of the other forums that we were talking about this way
那么也许你可以把问题和答案添加到我们刚才讨论过的其他论坛上
it will be indexed next time you or somebody else, Google's it
这样可以方便其他人以后通过 Google 检索到这个问题
now these quicker chat forums are places more for
现在这些快速聊天论坛更多是
the community to congregate and have quick conversations with each other.
社区成员聚集和快速交流的地方
They're places to theory craft, talk about new things coming out new ideas, events,
这些地方可以用来探讨理论问题，谈论新事物，新想法，新事件
and other things that shouldn't be indexed by web crawlers.
以及其他不应该被网络爬虫索引到的东西
They're also great places to meet and network with people
这些地方也是与他人会面和交流的好地方
that you might be able to bounce ideas off directly as you get to know each other,
你可以在与人相互了解的过程中直接交流想法
which leads into our last section.
这就引出了我们的最后一部分
But before we do that, Oh, do you hear that?
但在此之前，啊哦！你听到了么
Oh, that's the video inside another video alarm ringing.
哦！这是另一个视频里的视频警报响了
When you ask a question in one of these forums,
当你在这些论坛中提问时
the better you format your questions, the better chance you'll have of getting an answered.
你提问的格式越好，被回答的可能性就越高
Now there's no bad questions out there. But there are poorly formatted questions.
没有不好的问题，但确实有不好的提问方式
So let's teach you how to always ask questions as format as best as possible
所以让我来教一下你如何尽可能地以最好的格式提问
to give you the highest chance of making sure they get answered.
以此来确保问题会尽可能地被回答
Number one, before asking your question, make sure you followed all the steps in the parent video.
第一点，在提问之前，确保你遵循了前面视频中的所有步骤
And you've done some research on this already
并且已经做了充分的研究
and make sure the question hasn't already been asked.
确保这个问题还没有人问过
Number two, make a title that summarizes the specifics of the question
第二点，制定一个能够概括问题细节的标题
three introduced the problem before you write any code,
第三，在你放代码之前大致介绍一下问题的由来
add minimalistic, reproducible code
(第四) 添加一段简洁，可复现的代码
minimalistic code means it's not just a copy paste your entire file.
代码简洁的意思就是你不要直接复制粘贴你的整个文件
If you're having problems on one line,
如果你在某一行遇到了问题
maybe just post that one line
那就只发这一行就行了
reproducible code means that others should be able to run to
代码可复现的意思就是其他人运行这段代码时
the exact same error that you're running into,
应当能遇到和你完全相同的错误信息
or at least post the steps for them to do it.
或者至少说明一下他们应该做哪些步骤
This doesn't mean that you should put I was following along Patrick's video and on our five I ran into this problem,
但这意思并不是让你说，我正在看 Patrick 的视频，在视频第五小时的地方我遇到了这个问题
just watch his video and you'll get there.
去看一下他的视频你就明白我在说什么了
As flattering as this is it's not reasonable that everyone is going to have watched my videos,
虽然这让我受宠若惊，但是让所有人都来看我的视频是不合理的
even though they should
即使他们确实应该来看一下
you want to give the technical steps to reach the error that you've reached.
你应该给出运行出错误的确切技术步骤
For those of you watching my Free Code Camp video,
对于那些观看我 Free Code Camp 视频的人来说
you're kind of exempt from this,
你可以不受此限制，
but you can only say, Hey, I was on our Five on this part of your video inside of our discussions tab of the GitHub repo associated with this course.
但你只能在我们的与课程关联的 Github 仓库的讨论区说，嘿，我在视频第五小时的这部分...
So you can do that.
你是可以这样做的
But only in that GitHub repo associated with this course,
但必须只能是在与课程关联的 Github 仓库里
learning markdown to format your code,
(第五) 学习 Markdown 来格式化你的代码
especially using these three backticks and labeling of the language.
特别是这种三个点搭配语言标记的语法
This is a critical piece of formatting your code and will drastically improve on the number of people who answer your questions.
这是格式化代码的关键，它将极大地提升回答你问题的人数
Any errors or code should be formatted with this three backticks syntax.
任何报错信息和代码都应该用这种三个点的语法进行格式化
And finally,
最后一点
often people who care about certain technologies,
通常关注某些技术的人
monitor specific tags and monitor specific questions being asked about the technologies that they like.
会留意他们所关注的技术的特定标签 (tag) 和特定问题
And then finally, again,
最后再强调一下
be sure to read the forum's guides before posting
发帖之前一定要阅读一下论坛的指南
different forums have different rules about what they want and what they don't want.
不同的论坛对允许什么不允许什么有不同的规定
So being familiar will increase your chances of getting an answer.
熟悉这些会增加你被回答的概率
All right. So now back to the main video.
好了，现在回到主视频
Now a note about Stack Overflow, in particular,
得特别说一下 Stack Overflow
Stack Overflow can be a little aggressive,
Stack Overflow 可能会有点，咄咄逼人
which is why sometimes posting on specific community forums
这就是为什么有时在某些特定的社区论坛上发帖
might be better for your specific technology questions.
会更好地解决你的特定技术问题
If you post on Stack Overflow, and you get a ton of down votes on your questions.
如果你在 Stack Overflow 上发帖，然后你的问题收到了大量点踩的话
Don't let that bother you. Just take it as a learning opportunity
别太在意这个事了，就把它当作一个学习机会
to learn about what Stack Overflow likes and doesn't like
了解一下 Stack Overflow 偏好什么不偏好什么
and just keep going but do not let that discourage you.
继续前进，不要气馁
Okay, well, now that we know where things should go,
OKay，好了，现在我们知道该去哪里解决问题
where questions should go and how to actually format them.
去哪里提问并且是格式工整地提问
Let's practice let's look at some sample questions that you might have.
让我们来练习一下，一起来看几个你可能会遇到的例子
And we'll figure out where we want to put them.
我们一起来想办法看把它们放到哪里
So the first one, where does this one go? Feel free to pause and guess yourself.
那么这是第一个，应该放到哪里呢？暂停一下猜猜看
So a question like this is going to be great for a Reddit or a discord? Probably more a discord.
像这样的问题比较适合放到 Reddit 或者 Discord 上对吧？可能更多是 Discord
Now, this is definitely something that you can search for. Right?
这绝对是你可以搜索到的东西，对吧？
So you probably could search for this, find an answer and go from there.
你可以搜索一下，找到答案，然后根据答案开始学习
But maybe you want to ask a buddy or maybe you want to ask a very specific community like our slash eat Dev.
你也可以问问你的朋友或者问一些特定的社区比如我们的 /ethdev
Now, of course, if you see this question,
当然，如果你看到这类问题
you obviously want to recommend Patrick Collins his YouTube channel.
很明显，你就可以推荐 Patrick Collins 的 Youtube 频道
Now how about this question.
那么这个问题呢？
Notice its formatting right? The title is nice and big.
注意，它进行了格式化，对吧？标题又大又好看
They have a technical command that is formatted properly.
他们有格式正确的技术指令
They have Git commit which is formatted properly, where would this go
他们有正确地格式化了 git commit，这个怎么样
like this would definitely do very well on a Stack Overflow or an index code based forum
像这样的问题，在 Stack Overflow 或基于索引代码的论坛上肯定会做得更好
to very clearly try had to do something technical.
很明显，他们要做一些技术性的事情
The problem is laid out very clearly.
这个问题已经说得很清楚了
And they've given the command that they're looking to do.
并且他们也提供了他们想要执行得命令
Now, how about this one,
那么这个呢
something like this could go on either StackOverflow.
这样的问题可以放在 Stack Overflow 得以太坊版块上
But it's probably more likely going to go on a GitHub issue for this brownie package.
但更好的选择是放到 brownie 包的 Github issue 上
A big difference between code forums and and Git repos like GitHub is
代码论坛和像 Github 这样的 Git 仓库之间的一个很大的区别就是
that when you make an issue on a GitHub repository,
当你在 Github 仓库上发起一个 issue 时
especially when you think there's a problem, you do want to be as in depth as possible.
尤其是当你觉得这个问题，你希望尽可能地深入进去时
So oftentimes, when making an issue on these repos,
很多时候，这些仓库被发起 issue 的时候
they'll even ask, what version are you using?
他们甚至会问，你用的是哪个版本
Can you post all your code?
你可以发布你完整的代码么
Can you post all your files and just be much, much more explicit?
你能不能把你所有的文件都贴出来，再明确一点？
So how about something like this.
那么像这样的怎么样
So this is going to be really good for the GitHub repo associated with this tutorial,
像这样的就很适合放在与教程关联的 Github 仓库上
it looks like this person is asking about a very specific tutorial.
这个人看起来是在问一个非常具体的教程
So posting this, there is going to be best.
所以到那里发帖，是最高效的
Now if your question is on a tutorial that doesn't have a GitHub repo, well, they probably should.
如果你要询问的教程没有 Github 仓库的话，好吧，其实他们应该要有
But then maybe this is better in the comment section.
但没有的话你就需要把问题放到评论区里了
Now, again, this is where this all becomes a little bit more art than science,
现在，这搞得有点像艺术而不是科学了
because maybe the specific error that they're running into
因为有可能他们遇到的问题
is a generic error that a ton of people run into,
是一个很多人都遇到过的常见错误
and maybe it is better on StackOverflow.
这可能放到 Stack Overflow 上比较好
Or maybe there's an issue with the package. So maybe it is better on GitHub.
或者可能是软件包有问题，所以可能更适合去 Github
Or maybe the solution to this is opinionated.
或者，可能解决方案是坚持自己的想法
And finally, what about this?
最后，看一下这个呢？
Yep, this is going to be much better for a discord or a DM with your buddy.
是的，这个比较适合在 Discord 或者是和你的朋友在 DM 上讨论
And away, it's our last step on blocking you from any question
不管怎么样，你解决所有问题的最后一步都是
is going to be join and strengthen the community of your tool.
加入并强化你所使用的那个工具的社区
Now at the start, it's going to be hard for you to give back
开始的时候，你很难获得什么实际的回报
since you're not going to be very knowledgeable on these tools.
因为你对这些工具还不是很了解
But as you get better at these technologies,
但随着你越来越精通这门技术
you'll want to try to answer some of these new questions that do come in.
你会变得想要试着回答一些新出现的问题的
The reason is because this will give you a chance to actually learn more about the tools that you like,
这是因为这种行为可以给你一个机会让你进一步了解你热爱的这个工具
it'll strengthen the community of your favorite tools,
它还会强化这个工具的社区
meaning if you help answer questions on tool,
意思就是如果你帮助回答有关这个工具的问题
it'll actually encourage other people to use the tool because there's a strong following there.
它就会鼓励其他人坚持使用这个工具，因为这里有许多强大的追随者
And likely, they might actually help you sometime in the future,
而且很可能，未来的某一天他们会反过来再帮到你
you helping people will make you look like a good person.
帮助其他人也会让你看起来是一个好人
And then you'll also feel like a good person.
然后，你也会感到自己其实就是一个好人
Additionally, in many forums like Reddit,
此外，还有很多论坛，比如 Reddit
oftentimes, mods will actually look at how often you post
通常，mod(Reddit 的管理员) 会查看你发帖的频率
versus how often you help others and comments on others people posts
以及你帮助和评论其他贴子的频率
and some mods may actually start blocking your posts for abusing the forums
有些 mod 可能会因为你滥用论坛而屏蔽你的贴子
and not giving back to the community and only trying to take knowledge
并且请加入社区并帮助他人而不要只做个伸手党
you in the community will be more successful if you join in and help others and not just try to extract things from other people.
如果你热衷于加入并帮助别人，而不仅仅是只想从别人那里获得什么的话，你所在的社区将会更加繁荣
Additionally, by engaging with the community,
此外，通过参与社区
I can't tell you how many people I've met and I've learned
我无法说清楚，我到底遇到了多少人，学到了多少东西
and been able to brainstorm with.
并且我还能够与他们一起进行头脑风暴
And then the final step is going to be iterate through these steps.
最后的最后就是，不断重复这些步骤
Maybe you get to the end of these and you say, Oh, I'm still blocked,
也许你最后会说，啊，我还是没能解决这个问题
but you'll likely be much, much more knowledgeable.
不过你会因此而获得更多更多的知识
So you want to go back and try these steps again.
所以你可以回去再一次尝试这些步骤
Now this is where this whole process is a little bit more art than science.
这就是整个过程更有点像艺术而不是科学的地方
Because some questions might not have been discovered yet.
因为有些问题可能还没有被发现
Only very few people know
或者是只有很少的人明白怎么回事
not enough people understand the importance of the questions,
也可能是没有足够的人意识到问题的严重性
or maybe people don't understand your question.
或者人们可能不太理解你的问题
And this is why it's important to go back and iterate on these steps.
这就是为什么返回去重复这些步骤这一点这么的重要
Now that you have the basic building blocks of this incredible superpower,
现在你已经拥有了这个不可思议的超能力的基本组成部分
I encourage all of you to go out there and try this
我非常鼓励你们所有人都迈出这一步尝试一下
and then let me know how it went.
然后来告诉我一下结果如何